<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="intro"
      xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      version="5.0" xml:lang="en">

  <title>Introduction</title>
  <para>
    Today, all mobile platform has it's own Push platform used to deliver
    asynchronous messages.
  </para>
  <para>
    All these platforms have a common denominator, all of them maintains a TCP
    socket opened all the time.
  </para>
  <para>
    This socket will be used to deliver the notifications when it's needed.
  </para>
   
  <section>
    <title>Current Internet solutions issues</title>
    <para>
      Internet PUSH solutions are based on a public accesible server which
      handles all the notification delivery.
    </para>
    <para>
      These solutions were designed without considering the mobile networks
      way of working and forces the handset to maintain an open socket with
      the server in order to avoid misnotifications.
    </para>
    <para>
      This way of working increases the signalling and the handsets battery
      consume.
      For more information about this, please refer to the
      "<xref linkend="network_issues" endterm="network_issues_title" />" chapter
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Service Description</title>
    <para>
      The WakeUp platform is aimed to wakeup mobile devices so PUSH servers
      can avoid opening sockets all the time.
    </para>
    <para>
      The main objective of this service is to deliver wakeup packeges based
      on some user information given by the PUSH platform. It's designed to
      work in cellular networks environments.
    </para>
    <para>
      This server will provide a public API for trusted partners which allow
      them to wakeup any mobile device inside mobile operator networks.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>What is supposed third party PUSH platforms will use this</title>
    <para>
      Third party PUSH platform providers like Mozilla FirefoxOS PUSH server
      should sign an agreement with mobile operators to have access to the
      wake up public APIs
    </para>
    <para>
      Third party clients will benefict of the battery safe of their devices
      and reduce the network compsumption on any country.
    </para>
    <para>
      After sign the agreement, the Operator will deliver a signed certificate
      which identifies in a unique way the wakeup platform users.
    </para>
    <para>
      This certificate SHALL be used to Authenticate and Authorizate access to
      the WakeUp platform.
    </para>
  </section>
</chapter>
